[Music]
hey welcome to the connecting with code
camp this video is just for the adults
right so some things to come we play the
background the camp are not exciting and
don't don't have the kids join me for
this one just the adults watch this and
so you kind of know what's up
so I'm Dave Fisher I'm a college
professor at rolls Holman every summer
we offer a connecting with code camp the
idea of this camp is it's really
targeted for K through 8 students and
we're trying to learn a couple establish
a mindset where they like to code
there's lots of reasons to code I mean
who knows how many different websites
with different reasons to code and
everybody always thinks it's like
because you want to become a computer
scientist when you grow up I'd say that
would be great there's definitely need
but if you look at like this 10 reasons
kids should learn to code it's for like
improving their other skills right and
then number 10 is maybe career
preparation so that's kind of the
motivation for awhile we run the camp
we've run this camp for a total of four
years this year is very different than
any previous year in the past we always
do it unrolls Holmen campus we hire
Ruhlman students to participate this
year it's got to be a video right that's
just kind of the time when we live in
right now we're offering two camps this
one is called the scratch camp which is
a terrible name because we're actually
changing from scratch to something
called tinker instead so maybe you
already know scratch reviewer familiar
of scratch scratch is a website it's
great we're actually gonna do the whole
thing with with tinker instead and
hopefully you watch the the log in video
to see how to get the log in but tinker
can do the same thing as a scratch and
it's the same coding concept so to me
it's not different but yeah but the
title is different and so that's kind of
what our goal is and this camp we're
going to be doing it for a total of five
days together I wanted to tell you just
a little bit about what I expect from
you so that you kind of know what's
going on so I expect that you've
received a login for me you can get in
to tinker with your kiddo and what
tinker is is it's really two things
it's projects which is what we're going
to do together in video so we're going
to go up
to my projects when we do things
together but then it's also activities
that you can do by yourself
so there's a lot of activities you can
do by yourself I've just put a couple up
so far a great one is called dragon
spells if you're enjoying a program with
your kid I won't go through all the
titles but there's a lot of things in
there there's also a lot of stem lessons
which are really cool things to kind of
learn about and after we've done a few
things together what you'll be able to
tackle anything I just to kind of show
you really briefly what one of these
looks like maybe I'll go into like the
Barbie one Barbie kind of introduces you
to tinker which I kind of like it's
great for girls obviously but the boys
are walking I doing it as well but these
are more like puzzles that you solve
right so in this one I'm to the step
where Barbie starts
solving her first puzzle right so we
want to use the the new costume command
and I'm going to get it wrong here and
so you're going to put on some code and
so that one was actually not the correct
answer and the idea with this one it
actually told me anything earlier you
need to keep using next costume to solve
the puzzle so the way these work is you
actually have code in your workspace
over here and you drag it over to
connect it over here and Barbie will go
through explaining tinker to you better
than I could by far but these are
puzzles that you try to slow on right
and so here I think that I've got the
solution to Barbies puzzle I'm not even
sure of that but hopefully it worked now
well I'm sure I can get us another time
so that's what we're gonna be doing on
your own and then what we're going to be
doing together is we're going to be
building projects and you'll see these
quite a bit but if you go to my projects
we're going to be creating a lot of new
projects together and this interface is
really a lot like scratch and that's
what we're going to be spending our time
in and I think that the kids are going
to really like it alright so we look
forward to to having you join our first
actual video but I wanted to give the
parents some background about what this
camp was and kind of what we expect from
you so see you when we start doing
things on Monday
[Music]